

67 Olympic Place, 
London, Ontario,
Canada – N6G 3P8
+1-647-470-3597 
varughese.juby@gmail.com



#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm a creative developer offering over 2 years of experience developing high visibility web solutions across various industries. I'm experienced with designing, developing, and testing multiple web-based applications using a range of technologies in an Agile product development team. Always aspiring to combine broad technical skills and experience as a Full Stack Software Engineer.



## **TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY**

- Go, Python, PHP, JavaScript (React.js, Redux, and TypeScript), CMS (WordPress)
- Laravel, Django Rest Framework, SQL databases (MySQL, PostgreSQL),
- CSS (LESS and SASS preprocessors),
- UI design tools (Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator),
- Jest, Webpack, Google Analytics, Static Site Generators (Hugo), Linux, and Digital Ocean, RESTful APIs, version control (Git), Nginx



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | BCI INNOVATION LABS LONDON, ONTARIO

MAY 2020 - CURRENT

- Successfully developed websites from front to backend using TypeScript, React, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, PHP, Python and GO.
- Enhanced user experience and accomplished webpage objectives by creating site structure, navigation, page optimization, and graphics integration.
- Implemented enhancements that improved web functionality and responsiveness.
- Designed and maintained both corporate and client websites, using scripting languages and content management systems including WordPress.
- Increased performance metrics by 45% for all WordPress sites which resulted in more customers being brought into the system.
- Led a team of developers in building an online web platform.
- Coaching and training of other team members and external customers to ensure all stakeholders are confident in using software applications.
- Monitored quality and performance of applications through testing and maintenance.

# JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER | MIKA SOFTWARE CORPORATION

#### LONDON, ONTARIO

APRIL 2020 - JULY 2021

- Implemented Frontend platforms on React.js from pure HTML and CSS.
- Efficient Quality Assurance inspections on both Frontend and Backend to ensure errorfree applications.
- Assisted Senior Frontend Developers and Backend Developers with multiple tasks.

- Effectively communicated with native and remote developers, which helps work collaboratively.
- Developed Hugo site with eCommerce integration that generated revenue for an international client.
- Wrote documentation using markdown programming language to save time with document styling.



#### EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT & INTERNET APPLICATIONS
CERTIFICATE, CONESTOGA COLLEGE (JANUARY 2022 – AUGUST 2022)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT AND TECHNOLOGY ENTREPRENEURSHIP DIPLOMA, LONDON LANGUAGE INSTITUTE (SEPTEMBER 2019 – AUGUST 2021)

ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING
B.ENG, MAHATMA GANDHI UNIVERSITY (JULY 2013 - NOVEMBER 2017)



## SIDE PROJECTS

#### **PRODUCT – TRAVEL APP**

The app was developed using PHP and Laravel. Open-source API was used for travel booking, giving users an in-depth understanding of their favourite destinations before planning. The newsletter feature will enable us to send out weekly newsletters to all subscribers.

#### **PRODUCT - PILLSHARE**

A miniature medical web application version built on React, TypeScript, Golang and Firebase. It tracked the vital signs and user drug intakes, and the data could be shared with loved ones anywhere. This platform focuses primarily on monitoring the aging population's health and promoting their health stats.

#### **PRODUCT - BIODB**

A prototype API platform has been built on Python and Django Rest Framework. It was proposed to use Apple Health Kit data (the iPhone and the iWatch) to calculate statistics, generate graphs, and backup health kit data records using ETL functions to allow users to store their documents in a database that can then be pulled for the graph generation.



## **COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT**

Developer meetups, Volleyball, exploring the outdoors. Volunteered at a mission serving food to the needy.